The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Reporting to Ancestor,
some cultivators in the pavilion are suspected
Yun Meng\NTreasure Refining Pavilion
to be Soul Formation.
Soul Formation cultivators ?
Sun Dian\NOwner of the Treasure Refining Pavilion\NMiddle stage Soul Formation
Treasure Refining Pavilion
This person has 2 peak Nascent Soul guards...
He must be Soul Formation, the same level as the City Lord.
Please wait here Senior,
the auction will begin shortly.
Who's the one
that dared to block my Divine Sense ?
S...Soul Formation ?
Junior didn't know Senior was here,
I hope you'll forgive me.
Fellow cultivator Qiu,
long time no see.
Wang Lin ?
You ..
are actually Soul Formation ?
I see that our auction
has attracted quite a few fellow Soul Formation cultivators.
Thank you for coming.
If you guys like anything,
feel free to bid.
If you have artifacts,
my Treasure Refining Pavilion can also appraise them.
I wish you all
the best of luck.
It's him !
Note: This is a scene that was cut from episode 38. In it, Wang Lin and Qiu Siping meet after his killing spree in the Sea of Devils due to the Restriction Flag's tribulation. Sun Dian takes Wang Lin as disciple and puts a restriction on him. Wang Lin expelled that restriction from his body and escaped.
Junior is in a hurry.
We hope that Senior
can let us go.
You're exactly what I was looking for,
do you want to be my disciple ?
Junior is willing.
Fellow cultivator Sun,
do you remember me ?
I was reckless with you in the past,
I hope fellow cultivator Wang can forgive me.
In less than 200 years,
that Core Formation cultivator
has actually reached Soul Formation.
Your cultivation is higher than mine.
I'm the one
that needs your teachings.
I wonder what kind of treasure
fellow cultivator Wang is here for ?
The grade 6 pill recipe.
If it was anything else,
I would be able to help you.
but this rank 6 pill recipe is something someone else asked us to sell.
I... really can't help you.
No problem.
If I can't buy it,
I'll just steal it to make a copy.
This guy looks mannered
but he's a killer.
What if he really started a fight
in my pavilion...
The next item
is a valuable treasure.
I'm sure
everyone here already knows
that it's a pill recipe
for a grade 6 pill.
Grade 6 pills
are items only the country of Suzaku can produce.
Grade 6 pill recipe ?
I'm lucky to see this in my lifetime.
But if you have the recipe, you can also do it.
We all know
the value of this item.
I'll leave it at that.
At the owner's request
the starting price
is 10 000 high quality spirit stones.
10 000 high quality spirit stones ?!
Who can afford that ?
How many people in the Sea of Devils have this much ?
Okay...
Do fellow cultivators have a bid ?
Celestial jades are more valuable than spirit stones.
But if I use them,
it will blow my cover
and trigger a search by the country of Suzaku.
I...
offer this item.
Alright.
Fellow cultivator,
have you ever seen something like this ?
Fellow cultivator Wang,
these blood veins inside the wood carving...
Could they possibly be...
Xue Yue’s puppet crafting technique ?
I have never seen anything like this before,
however we are sure that
this item is the same as a Late stage Nascent Soul puppet.
We price it
5000 high quality spirit stones.
Don't worry fellow cultivator,
this Junior doesn't know what he's talking about.
The blood vein alone could double the price of that carving.
Not to mention
the hint of a Soul Formation's domain inside it.
Fellow cultivator,
I will buy
your artifact.
This purple jade
can be traded at my pavilion
for 20 000 high quality spirit stones.
20 000 high quality spirit stones.
20 000 ?
My lady here
offers 30 000 high quality spirit stones.
30 000 ?!
Here's another bidder...
You're really screwing me up !
If this kid really does it...
Brother Wang,
I have
4 000 spirit stones you can use.
No need.
You stay here and guard her.
Sure.
Junior Zi Xin
greets Senior.
If you can't give me
a good reason for luring me here,
don't blame me for being ruthless.
Senior is very cunning.
This little girl admires you.
Don't bullshit me !
You have just reached Soul Formation
and you comprehended someone else's domain.
Stand down !
You overestimate yourself.
Senior,
Junior was rude,
but I was forced to.
Please Senior,
in exchange for the grade 6 pill recipe,
can you help me ?
Junior
is from the Faint Mist Sect of Zhou.
My father is the Sect Leader.
20 years ago,
he entered the Immortal Graveyard
and still hasn't returned.
This Immortal Graveyard
is one of the 2 most dangerous places on Suzaku,
on par with the Nine Ghost Desolate Valley.
Junior's cultivation
isn't strong enough.
I hope Senior can accompany me there
to retrieve my father’s remains.
I don't have time.
This jade slip is worth 20 000 high quality spirit stones,
consider it the payment for this copy.
In this formula of the Return to Origin pill
137 herbs and ingredients of all kinds are recorded.
It's incredibly difficult to refine.
Moreover,
most of these herbs are extremely rare
or long extinct.
The sect
has less than 20 of those in stock.
For the remaining
we will have to study them individually
to find substitutes.
Wan'er's body
doesn't have much more time.
Mobilize the whole Cloud Sky Sect.
Regardless of the cost,
if we have the ingredients
we use them.
If we don't,
we'll trade for them at a high price.
Some herbs in this formula
are treasures even in rank 4 and rank 5 countries.
This...
Then I'll go get them myself.
It's here !
There's more here.
Got it.
Find them all, quick !
Yes !
Paying respect to Senior.
All the grade 4 alchemists in the sect
have come here.
Wrong !
It's all wrong !
In combining properties of medicinal herbs,
there's no room for error !
No more errors
or I will kick you out of the Cloud Sky Sect !
Wan'er,
this energy comes from my Life and Death Domain.
Let's see if it works.
I feel
a bit better.
It's just that I'm suddenly sleepy.
You're weak now.
In order for this life energy to work,
you need to rest.
You can relax.
Senior,
Wan'er is not afraid of death.
What I fear
is that I'll never see you again.
You won't die,
I promise.
Top of the Julu mountain
Heaven Carving Lotus
The lotus that blooms only once every 300 years...
Tianfan Sect Elder\NEarly stage Soul Formation
I'm finally done waiting !
A thief !
How dare you rob me ?!
You won't get out alive !
Those who try to stop me
will die !
Don't be afraid,
I'm here.
Go to sleep,
I'll stay with you.
More death aura...
Wan'er's condition is getting worse and worse.
Not good enough !
Go find better ones !
Soul Destruction Sect\NCountry of Julu
Bring it !
Phantom Sect\NShang Lin Country
The Ancestor
is really hard-working.
He's been all over the planet to look for ingredients
and he always comes back before the Sect Leader wakes up.
Each time she sleeps,
it takes longer before she awakens...
In these 2 years since my return to Chu,
I have nourished Wan'er with spiritual energy.
But she is still growing weaker and weaker.
If she tries to reach Nascent Soul by force now,
she might not even be able to form her soul
and her body won't be able to handle it.
At that moment,
the incomplete Nascent Soul
will only dissipate.
I won't even be able to extract her soul...
I did it !
Ancestor,
I found the substitute
for the last 3 ingredients !
I found a combination of 37 other ingredients that will have the same effect.
Most are common
but one is very unique.
It's found in the rank 4 country of the Yin-Yang Sect.
10 000 years ago, the Yin-Yang Sect's country was rank 5.
Please be careful this time !
Yin-Yang Sect
Yin-Yang Sect Ancestor\NLate stage Soul Formation
Who is this Junior
that dares to attack our sect !?
You're reckless !
Wan'er,
wait for me.
Senior !
The Ancestor has been gone for months,
we haven't heard from him at all.
Maybe something happened to him ?
Senior will be back.
He said that
he'd be back.
But...
I believe in him.
Quick !
Send her spiritual energy !
The three of us
can't suppress this !
Wan'er,
I'm back.
To overturn this fate,
I will walk against the heavens.
I will even gather the clouds
to illuminate the sky for you.
Senior
I told them that
All this sadness was not meaningless.
never breaks his promises.
How many lives and deaths have passed in the blink of an eye ?
I vow to break
Phantom Grass
Start the furnace,
this chess game of fate.
we're making this pill.
I vow to break
this chess game of fate.
Even if the heavens want you to die, I will steal you back.\NWan'er, this is my promise to you.
Battle with the law of the heavens
Falling from the night sky and melting into dust\Nlike water without a source.
Like the difference between clouds and mud,\Nthe truth cannot be found in conflict.
Life and death\Nare like the moment when the rain falls
and like many other unseparable things.
In this lifetime,\Nto cultivate the truth, cultivate the world first.
Old grudges had to be settled\Nbecause half an inch is engraved into my tree rings.
Use the most vivid love and hate\Nto ask questions to your fate.
Let your eyes be filled enough with rage\Nto pierce the heart and the soul
then soften because of the mortals' fireworks.
Only when you bend down can you understand\Nthe hidden edge of the blade.
The human mind is nature,\Nthe rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,\Nthere are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart\Nto depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.\NAfter struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.\NEverywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined\Nby this endless world.
The human mind is nature,\Nthe rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,\Nthere are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart\Nto depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.\NAfter struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.\NEverywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined\Nby this endless world.
Snow falls as my hair turns white, winter withers\Nwhile prosperity sprouts in summer.
I step into the world, with light at my fingertips,\Nthe law of cause and effect.
I observe the vastness of heaven and earth so I can get rid of evil.
Obsession arises from one thought, life and death arise from one thought.\NReincarnation is not to be feared.